# **Austin Gathii**

# Software Engineer

Nairobi, Kenya ⋈ gathiiaustin@gmail.com \ +254 716611612 ☐ Github in LinkedIn **★** Personal Website

## **PROFILE**

I am a software engineer specializing in full-stack web development with Django and React. I am proficient with python which I have recently used along with SQL for large data analysis as well as in the past for personal projects.

I also have some experience with PHP and Android development with Java as a result of recent academic projects.

I am passionate about the future of computer technology and I enjoy working in organizations where I can meaningfully contribute to that future.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst Mar 2022 - present Nairobi, Kenya

Microhouse Technologies

- Managed, cleaned and maintained a large SQL database of user data in a team with 2 other engineers
- Analyzed said database to extract and derive trends and predictive data and used the matplotlib library in Python to visualize it.

## **Software Engineering Intern**

Iansoft Technologies Limited

- Assisted senior programmers in building enterprise software solutions over the course of a 3 month long internship
- Built the foundations of a car dealership enterprise software solution in Microsoft Dynamics together with 2 other interns that was further refined and adapted for real-world use.

## Web Developer

Smart Data Analytical Limited

- Developed a travel blogging site for a client based on Wordpress and created custom PHP plugins to fulfill more specific client requirements.
- Designed basic graphics and illustrations for an institution's website using Adobe Illustrator.

Feb 2021 - Apr 2021 Nairobi, Kenya

Jan 2020 - Apr 2020 Nairobi, Kenya

## **EDUCATION**

# Bachelor of Science, Informatics and Computer Science

Strathmore University

2018 – 2022 Nairobi, Kenya

May 2022 - Jul 2022

Jul 2021 - Feb 2022

Earned a bachelor's degree in Computer Science over the course of 4 years that included courses on the fundamentals of computer technology as well as several specializations in the field such as mobile development, web development and database management.

# **PROJECTS**

#### Personal Website 2

A fully responsive Javascript-based developer portfolio built on the React framework with SCSS for styling. The website is highly customizable which also allows it to serve as a template for other

developers.

# Attendance Tracking System 🛮

A python based system that integrates with a camera and touchpad to provide attendance tracking of personnel within an organization through the use of facial recognition technology.

Jul 2019 - Nov 2019

# Green Delight 🛮

An android based grocery shopping application that connects buyers and sellers on a virtual marketplace while also incorporating delivery riders who facilitate the physical transfer of groceries.

## **SKILLS**

## **Programming Languages**

Python, Javascript, Java, PHP, C++

## Front End

React, Jinja, SCSS, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS

### **Back End**

Django, Flask, Node.js

## **Databases**

SQL, SQLite